CHARLES GRIFFIN

Athens, GA 706.248.8851 ★ chuckgriffin1987@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/griffinchuck



FULL-STACK DEVELOPER ♦ PROJECT MANAGER ♦ APPLICATION PROGRAMMER

Software Development ★ System Design ★ Process Improvements

Analytical Full-Stack Developer / Engineer with an eye for detail and commitment to producing clean and well-structured code, specifically: *PHP/Laravel, AngularJS, C#, and .NET*. Four years in-field experience in application design and development. Media Studies graduate from the University of Georgia, Web Development graduate from Gwinnett Technical College, and current enrollee at prestigious Georgia tech Coding Bootcamp. A keen observer of trends and quick learner of programming languages with a passion for startups, innovative solutions, and helping teammates and clients succeed. Integral team member responsible for designing and crafting multiple applications for a large university, from initial concept through delivery of completed product.

SELECTED HIGHLIGHTS

- Integral team member responsible for designing and crafting multiple applications for a large university, from initial concept through delivery of completed product.
- Sole Creator and Developer of ScriptMother.com, a social media platform for aspiring authors and screenwriters.
 Designed and programmed every aspect of the immersive application from the ground up.
- Expertly oversaw all customer purchases for shop4futons.com online catalog to ensure customer satisfaction.
- Generated online product listings, including descriptions, images, and layout, with strict attention to detail.

CORE COMPETENCIES

- Application Programming
- Object-Oriented Technology
- Web Content Management
- Software Analysis and Design
- Database Design/Development
- Web Design and Development
- Application Testing
- Project Management
- E-Commerce Management

EDUCATION

Georgia Tech Professional Education, Online: 2019
Certifi cate – Online 24-week Coding Bootcamp
Gwinnett Technical College, Lawrenceville, GA: 2016

Diploma – Internet Specialist, Web Development and Design (GPA: 3.8/4.0)

The University of Georgia, Athens, GA: 2009 Bachelor of Arts – Journalism (GPA: 3.54/4.0)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Development & Alumni Relations, University of Georgia ♦ Athens, GA ♦ 2017 – Present Web Developer

- Utilize extensive programming and development skills to build and manage applications for UGA fundraising.
- Create and manage event registration and online donation pages for fundraising and marketing efforts.
- Build and maintain customizations for existing system applications.
- Coordinate with team members and departments to provide application support for marketing efforts and goals.

AIBN Radio → Athens, GA → 2016 – 2017 Media Coordinator/Web Developer

- Utilize extensive programming skills to create and maintain the podcast website, <u>www.thedannydanielshow.com</u>.
- Proficiently manage all copywriting, analytics and hard coding of the website, ensuring all deadlines are met.
- Employ front-end development with client-side validation, middle-tier development, and back-end management.
- Brainstorm the technical and workflow solutions to ensure website functionality meets business requirements.

Charles Griffin Résumé – Page 2

F & F Distributors – Shop4futons.com, World of Futons ♦ Athens, GA ♦ 2013 – 2017 Web Designer/Online Manager

- Expertly oversee all customer accounts and purchases for online catalogs to ensure customer satisfaction.
- Efficiently generate online product listings, including descriptions, images, and layout, with strict attention to detail.
- Direct social media and brand development, generating bi-monthly blog posts related to furniture and comfort living and managing Facebook page and other social media accounts to increase brand awareness.
- Coordinate daily with wholesale manufacturer to ensure all orders are processed and shipped accordingly.

The Institute of Continuing Legal Education in Georgia (ICLE Georgia) ♦ Athens, GA ♦ 2016 – 2017 Web Manager/IT Administrator

- Created, managed and oversaw web content for all seminars provided by ICLE Georgia.
- Set up and maintained live web streams and online video courses for all seminars.
- Routinely updated web content according to current schedule, and ensured flawless functionality of website.
- Coordinated with IT administrators and third-party consultants to increase efficiency of IT environment.

Additional Experience:

Industry Bound (<u>www.industrybound.com</u>) – Owner, Creator, Web Developer/Designer ScriptMother (<u>www.scriptmother.com</u>) – Founder, Owner, Web Developer/Designer Cedalius International (www.cedalius.com) - Web Designer, UX/UI

Upper Oconee Watershed Network (<u>www.uown.org</u>) – Web Designer, UX/UI

Goldcrest Films, New York, NY: 2010 – 2011, Script Reader

Cox Radio, Athens, GA: 2009 – Present, Board Operator/Studio Producer/Traffic Reporter

New York Office Talent Agency, New York, NY: 2008, Intern

TECHNICAL SKILLS	
PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES/LANGUAGES	HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP, Node.js, Ajax, XML
DATABASES	MySql, Oracle, MongoDB
Software	Dreamweaver, Photoshop, Microsoft Office, Eclipse, Visual Studio
DEVELOPMENT SOFTWARE TOOLS	Windows Communication Foundation, WordPress, GitHub
FRAMEWORKS	Bootstrap, AngularJS, JUnit, Laravel

Additional Credentials	
HONORS AND AWARDS	 Screenplay of the Month – Trigger Street Productions
	■ Highest Customer Satisfaction Ratings — UberPrints.com
PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT	 Certified IT Analysis, Design, & Project Management
	Fluency in full-stack design and development for mobile devices
	Program Design and Development
ORGANIZATIONS	 Team Treehouse Member – Online Tech and Coding Community
	 United States Chess Federation – Lifelong Member
VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE	Chess Coach, Barrow Elementary, Clark Middle School, Athens, GA / Volunteer Mentor, Board Member, HarlemLive Journalism Program, New York, NY
INTERESTS	Screenwriting, audio/radio production, exercise

Detailed Professional References Available upon Request

444